<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Beamng Drive Guide</string>
    <string name="text1">Modifiers, as their name implies, can modify the track you created. There are three kind of modifiers: Banking, Height and Width. Banking modifiers can be used to create banked turns, which are important in fast and curvy tracks. Height modifierslet you create slopes, hills and valleys. The Width Modifier can create wider and slimmer tracks. All of those Modifiers work through Markers which are placed on the track, in between the pieces. The markers define the value that a marker has, for example the actual elevation of a height marker. Once you have two of more markers of the same kind on your track, the system will interpolate the values and modify the pieces between those markers accordingly. In the Main Window, you can use the modifier buttons to create a marker after the currently selected piece and so change the bank, height or width of the track. Furthermore, you can use the modify button to create a new marker with value of the previous marker at the current position, use the trash bin button to remove a marker at the current position, or use the reset button to create or set a marker at the current position to its base value. You can also shift markers to the next or previous piece by using the arrow buttons next to the modifier buttons. Bank markers are red rectangles that are tiled according to their bank value at the center of a piece. The base value for banking is 0°. Height markers are blue columns below a piece. The base value for height is 0m. Width markers are green spheres at the borders of a piece. The base value for width is 10m.
</string>
    <string name="text2">"The Track Builder is an Ingame Editor which lets you create 3D tracks. You have control over a variety of things: Create the track from multiple, individually tweakable track pieces like straights, curves, spirals and loopings. Modify the bank, height and width of the track using a marker system. Select different border shapes for individual pieces and sides. Customize your track by creating your own materials and paint individual pieces. Place obstacles like pillars and ramps on your track to keep drivers on their toes. Create walls and ceilings of varying heights to form tunnels or narrow passages. Test, Save, Load and share your tracks. "</string>
    <string name="text3">"To open the Track Builder, either select the entry from the main menu, or select the Track Builder icon from the side menu when in freeroam mode. On your screen, you will then see the following: 1: Main Window: The big window with the header \"Track Builder\" is the Main Window. This contains the basic functionality to create a track. a: Navigation: Use these buttons to select different pieces of the track. You can also click Pieces to select them. b: Pieces: Here you find different pieces to add to your track. c: Modifiers: These are modifiers which can change the bank, height and width of your track. d: Drive: Use these buttons to actually drive on your track. 2: Window Toolbar: At the top of the screen, on the left side is the Window Toolbar. Here you can open additional windows which offer advanced functionality. 3: Mouse Function Toolbar: Next to the Window Toolbar is the Mouse Function Toolbar. It will show you what happens when you click on a piece. 4: Track Beginning: In the center of the screen is the beginning of the track itself. You can then use the free camera controls: default keys are WASD to move the camera and hold right click to look around. "</string>
    <string name="text4">"Every Track in the Track Builder is at its core a list of pieces, which themselves have parameters that describe them. Pieces can for example be Straight, Curve, or Looping\", while parameters for these pieces could be Length, Radius or Offset. In the Main Window, you can add new pieces to the end of the track by clicking on a piece button. To change the piece parameters, use the buttons below the piece buttons. To remove a piece, use the remove piece button next to the pieces. There is also the option to replace the current piece with a different one by holding control while clicking the piece button. Also, you can insert a new piece directly behind the currently selected one by holding shift and clicking the piece button. "</string>
    <string name="text5">"To select a piece, you can click on it. The selected piece is highlighted in green. When adding a marker, it will be placed directly after the currently selected piece. Additionally, you can use the selection arrows at the top of the Main Window to navigate through the pieces one by one, or select the first or last piece of the track. You can also use the camera button to focus the camera on the currently selected piece. "</string>
    <string name="text6">"To actually drive on your track, you can use the Drive button at the bottom of the Main Window. This will repair your car and place it at the beginning of the track. You can also use the Test button to place your car at the current selection. Please note that the collision of the track is only updated when you drive or test your track. "</string>
    <string name="text7">"The track builder has a variety of things you can do. Every feature has its own window, which you can open by either clicking its icon on the toolbar at the top of the screen, or through the \"Windows\" menu entry on the top of the Main Window. "</string>
    <string name="text8">"The banking section has a row of Buttons for preset values ranging from -90° to 90°. Clicking on one of those will create a marker with the buttons value at the current selection. There is also a number input to set the banking to a custom value. You can also click and drag this input to change the banking smoothly. "</string>
    <string name="text9"><![CDATA["The height section allows you to modify the height in bigger steps. There is also an option to set a Custom Slope for this marker, which should be used if you want different interpolations in your track than the default smoothSlope and smootherSlope. Otherwise, there might be gaps at the position of the marker. Similar to the banking section, there is a number input to set the height to a custom value, which can also be dragged for smooth inputs. "]]></string>
    <string name="text10">"The width section gives you Buttons to set the width of the track to some preset values, as well as the regular buttons to make the track wider or slimmer. It also has a custom input which can be dragged. Note that the maximum width of a track is 50m. "</string>
    <string name="text11">"Each of the modifiers has a drop down list to select the way this modifier is interpolated. The interpolation is tied to a marker and affects the region between the marker itself and it's direct predecessor. For most tracks, smoothSlope and smootherSlope should be used, as they connect smoothly to the next interpolated section. "</string>
    <string name="text12">"This window gives you additional pieces to chose from. At the top of the window, you see buttons to select and navigate through pieces as well as focus the camera on the currently selected piece. Below that, there are the actual buttons to add pieces, and below that the buttons to change the parameters of the currently selected piece. "</string>
    <string name="text13">When you click on a piece button, a new piece of this type will be added to the end of the track. If you hold the shift button while doing so, the piece will instead be added right behind your selection. Holding the control button will cause the currently selected piece to be replaced by the piece you clicked.</string>
    <string name="text14">"The Bezier Piece is the most powerful piece. There are numerous Parameters you can change for this piece: X-/Y-Offset: This determines the end position of the piece. Forward and Backward Length: These determine how \"strongly\" the direction of the start or end of the piece influence the overall piece shape. Directional Offset: This determines the direction the piece will end in. Global/Local: This button switches between a two coordinate systems for this piece: If local is selected, the end position of the piece is offset from the start position of the piece. If global is selected, the end position of the piece is offset from the origin of the track. The Global setting is useful when you want all the pieces after this Bezier to stay in their position while you modify pieces before it. Solid/Empty: This button toggles whether the piece is solid or not. Empty pieces can be used to create gaps in your track. The Spiral pieces have a shape that is very useful for connecting curved and straight pieces. You can change the following: Radius: This changes the radius of the curved end of the piece. Spirals and Curves with the same Radius fit together perfectly. Length: This changes the end angle of the piece. Longer Length means the transition from straight to curve happens over a longer distance and is thus smoother. Please note that this piece's length can only be 30°, 45°, 60° or 75°. Inward/Outward: This sets the spiral to either transition from a straight to a curve, or from a curve to a straight. "</string>
    <string name="text15">"This window allows you to change the shape of the border of individual track pieces. You can select individual shapes for both sides of the tracks. To change the track shape, select a shape from the drop down list, make sure that the \"Draw\"-Checkbox of the side you want to modify is checked, and then click on the track piece you want to change. You can hold shift and click on a piece to select that pieces border shapes. You can also hold control and click on a piece to flood-fill modify the track: All adjacent pieces which have the same shape as the original piece will be changed to the shape you selected. This is useful if you want to modify a large section of track: simply change the last and first piece of the section, then flood-fill the pieces in between. Please make sure that, in order to actually change the shape of pieces, the top right toolbar has the shape symbol highlighted. To stop modifying pieces, either close the Shape Window or select the \"Selection\" symbol in the top right toolbar. "</string>
</resources>